[Music]
the fourth-quarter FF i-20 was most
eventful for life insurance companies
impacted by various events let's do a
three-point analysis to understand which
one should investors keep their focus on
one impact of budget proposals and
reinsurance rate hike well the union
budget had proposed an alternative tax
regime that allows no exemptions and
deductions but offers a lower tax rate
now there are concerns that this could
impact the future demand of life
insurance products or general insurance
products however both the insurers have
said that the alternative tax regime
would not impact them materially as the
industry as a whole has moved away from
a predominantly tax exemption driven
sales approach now the budget also
proposed the removal of the DDT or the
dividend distribution tax and made
dividends taxable at the hands of the
recipient which adversely impacted
margins growth and also return of both
life insurances now during the quarterly
insurers hiked their rates around 50% of
the salmon show a summer short in the
retail protection business pure term
insurance is usually reinsured I see I
see a proven HDFC life responded
differently to reinsurance rates hikes
on rates going up now I see a pro has
revised the pricing by increasing
premium for protection business that
fully absorbs the changes in the
reinsurance rates such that the margins
are maintained at the same level in
contrast HDFC life has not yet passed on
the reinsurance rate hikes to customers
rather it will look to maintain margins
by bringing down the acquisition cost
and retaining the book rather than
reinsuring it to impact of kovat 19
well the outbreak of kovat 19 has a
significant impact on business margins
returns and solvency of the insurance
companies new policy sales were severely
impacted in March as the country entered
the long term now apart from this
according to HDFC life it did see a
business hit to the tune of around 600
crore rupees in terms of renewable
premium renewal premium and also four to
five hundred crores in the new business
premium I see I see a pro is now using
digital sales method
such as video calling chat BOTS telling
medicals to drive the customer sales and
servicing now in addition to the
business go vid 19 has a significant
impact on the investment returns now as
far as the asset side is concerned HDFC
life made 106 crore rupees provision on
yes Bank 81 BOTS now I see a proof for
that it has not invested in a single
defaulting security over the last 20
years which is a big positive on the
liability side as well I say say Prue is
well-placed to tie it through the market
volatility both the life insurers
reported investment loss in FY 20
against the gain in FY 19 now instances
of insurance claims for kovat 19 are
miniscule so far despite the adverse
scenarios both the leading private
players ICICI Prudential Life and HDFC
life have seen acceleration in
profitability yardsticks in FY 2017 the
new business margins driven by higher
persistency lower expenses and also an
evolving product mix 3 where should
investors put their focus on our way
should you invest well around 65 to 75
percent of the value of life insurance
companies comes form the future new
business value vnb
and hence it remains the most important
metric while both HDFC life and ICS a
pro have shown accelerated growth here
Isis a pro has guided to double the new
business value by FY 23 implying a
compounded growth rate of 19 percent per
annum in effort 20 I say Sapru so the
new business value grow by about 21
percent which was very encouraging now
amongst the two players I say approves
business growth was thrower than HDFC
life in FY 20 with a PE or the
annualized premium equivalent falling by
5% that is because it saw D growth in
traditional EULA business but high
margin protection business growth for IC
April was very high the new value
business margins and the ro EB or the
return on embedded value at HDFC life
are the highest in the sector but having
acknowledged all these positives the
premium valuation of HDFC life leaves us
with cold feet HDFC life is trading at
four point seven times at 5:20 price to
embedded value I say I say approve stock
is currently
at 2.3 times up by 20 price to embed it
value which is a significant discount to
HDFC life now we do see this as an
opportunity for the investors the best
time to buy a stock during the downturn
during a downturn is when it is really
beaten down I see I say it's a very on
track to double the value of its new
business improve the business mix in
favour of protection business and
consequently also generate better
margins and return going forward so
investors wanting to participate in the
insurance growth story can do so by
investing in IC ICF true which is
available at a relatively compelling
valuation
[Music]